<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../XSLT/Avatar_CSS_7.css"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../XSLT/Avatar_XSLT_07.xsl"?>

<?xml-model href="../avatar_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<atla>
    <transcript>
        <head>
            <episode n="4">The Warriors of Kyoshi</episode>
            <book n="1">Water</book>
            <source link="https://avatar.fandom.com/wiki/The_Warriors_of_Kyoshi"/>
        </head>
        <charlist>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Katara">Katara</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Aang">Avatar</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Zuko">Zuko</charList>
        </charlist>
        <body>
            <scene n="1">
                <sp><spkr ref="Zuko">Zuko</spkr>Nice try, Avatar! But these little girls can't save
                    you.</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr><sd>Close-up of Zuko.</sd> Hey! Over here!</sp>
                <sd>Zuko turns around. Close-up of a determined Aang standing at the beginning of
                    the main street, holding his staff in front of him like he is challenging the
                    prince.</sd>
                <sp><spkr ref="Zuko">Zuko</spkr>Finally!</sp>
                <sd>Zuko commences by sending two fire balls in Aang's direction. Back view of Aang
                    as he prepares to face the incoming, burning projectiles. He ducks underneath
                    the first and uses his staff to decimate the next fire ball. He rapidly spins
                    the staff over his head, propelling himself in the air. He lands in front of
                    Zuko, who immediately kicks the staff out of his hands. Aang jumps up and lands
                    between two fans of a Kyoshi Warrior that are lying on the ground. He stands up
                    and picks us the fan with his airbending. Close-up of Zuko, who madly charges
                    Aang with his fist already held stretched out before him. Aang spins around a
                    few times to create a bigger momentum and uses the extra power of his swirl to
                    blast Zuko in a nearby house with a strong blast of air. Aang looks sad and
                    lowers the fans. He runs down the main street and picks up his staff along the
                    way. Aang tosses the object in the air, where it snaps open into his glider and
                    jumps on. A close-up of a saddened Aang, switches to the scene he is seeing: a
                    lot of burning houses and the Fire Nation troops among them. Aang looks back to
                    see the burning statue of Avatar Kyoshi, which saddens Aang even more.</sd>
                <sd>Cut to an overview shot of Katara as she is leading Koko and another village
                    girl into a house.</sd>
                <sp><spkr ref="Katara">Katara</spkr>Get inside.</sp>
                <sd>Aang lands and Katara turns to face him as he walks over to her.</sd>
                <sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr><sd>Sorrowful.</sd> Look what I brought to this
                    place.</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Katara">Katara</spkr>It's not your fault.</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr><sd>Close-up. Upset.</sd> Yes, it is. These people
                    got their town destroyed trying to protect me.</sp>
                <sd>Camera turns to Katara. Five little girls can be seen behind her in the house.
                    Koko stands in the doorway holding Momo, whole the girl next to her peeks around
                    the door frame with a worried look upon her face.</sd>
                <sp><spkr ref="Katara">Katara</spkr>Then let's get out of here. Zuko will leave
                    Kyoshi to follow us. I know it feels wrong to run, but I think it's the only
                    way.</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr><sd>Sad.</sd> I'll call Appa.</sp>
            </scene>
        </body>
    </transcript>
</atla>
