<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<avatarEpisode12>
    <transcript>
<scene><sd>As the flight of birds passes over Iroh's head in the distance, he sniffs the air and Zuko lowers the spyglass to turn to his uncle, who speaks.</sd>
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	There is a storm coming. A big one.
<speaker>Zuko</speaker>	You're out of your mind, Uncle. <sd>[Walking up to Iroh.]</sd> The weather's perfect. There's not a cloud in sight.
<sd>The shot cuts behind the two, facing the prow of the ship and showing a clear sea and sky.</sd>
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	A storm is approaching from the north. <sd>[He turns to face Zuko.]</sd> I suggest we alter our course and head southwest.
<speaker>Zuko</speaker>	<sd>[Taking a few steps in Iroh's direction, pointing briefly northward.]</sd> We know the Avatar is traveling northward, so we will do the same.
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	<sd>[Cut to his face; stern.]</sd> Prince Zuko, consider the safety of the crew.
<speaker>Zuko</speaker>	<sd>[Cut to his face as he advances on his uncle angrily.]</sd> The safety of the crew doesn't matter!
<sd>Behind them, Lieutenant Jee walks onto deck, inadvertently overhearing the conversation. As Zuko realizes Jee is behind him and turns to face him, his expression briefly loses its raging intensity. A quick close-up shows Jee raising an eyebrow as Zuko walks over to him; another cut shifts the view to the lieutenant's side as Zuko, addressing Jee directly, struts up to him, dominantly looking him right in the eyes from a close distance as he finishes speaking.</sd>
<speaker>Zuko</speaker>	Finding the Avatar is far more important than any individual's safety.
<sd>As Zuko walks away, Jee glares after him. The shot switches, showing Zuko leaving the deck through the door at the base of the superstructure. Cut to a frontal shot of Jee, who looks slightly enraged as Iroh walks over to him.</sd>
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	<sd>[Reassuringly, a twinge of uncertainty in his voice, almost as if he does not fully believe what he is saying.]</sd> He doesn't mean that. He's just all worked up.</scene>

<scene><sd>The scene changes back to Zuko's ship. Jee is talking about Zuko to a couple other men.</sd>
<speaker>Jee</speaker>	I'm sick of taking his orders! I'm tired of chasing his Avatar! I mean, who does Zuko think he is?
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	Do you really want to know?
<sd>Jee is shown standing up at the sound of Iroh's voice.</sd>
<speaker>Jee</speaker>	General Iroh. We were just- <sd>[Iroh cuts him off.]</sd>
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	It's okay. May I join you?
<speaker>Jee</speaker>	Of course, sir.
<sd>Iroh is shown sitting down.</sd>
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	<sd>[Massages his beard.]</sd> Try to understand. My nephew is a complicated young man. He has been through much.
<sd>Scene changes to a flashback. Zuko walks up to the curtains to get in the war room, but the guard on the left moves in front of the curtain to stop him.</sd>
<speaker>Young Zuko</speaker>	Let me in!
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	<sd>[Places his hands on Zuko's shoulders.]</sd> Prince Zuko, what's wrong?
<speaker>Young Zuko</speaker>	I want to go into the war chamber <sd>[Points to the guard.]</sd> but the guard won't let me pass!
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	<sd>[Leads Zuko away with his left hand still on his shoulder.]</sd> You're not missing anything, trust me. These meetings are dreadfully boring.
<speaker>Young Zuko</speaker>	If I'm going to rule this nation one day, don't you think I need to start learning as much as I can?
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	Very well. But you must promise not to speak. <sd>[Another elder soldier walks by them into the war chamber.]</sd> These old folks are a bit sensitive, you know?
<speaker>Young Zuko</speaker>	<sd>[Bows to Iroh.]</sd> Thank you, Uncle.
<speaker>Zuko</speaker> and Iroh walk into the war room. The meeting starts.
<speaker>Bujing</speaker>	The Earth Kingdom defenses are concentrated here. <sd>[Bujing shows the place on the map.]</sd> A dangerous battalion of their strongest earthbenders and fiercest warriors. So I am recommending the forty-first division.
<speaker>Elder Soldier</speaker>	But the forty-first is entirely new recruits. How do you expect them to defeat a powerful Earth Kingdom battalion?
<speaker>Bujing</speaker>	I don't. They'll be used as a distraction while we mount an attack from the rear. What better to use as bait than fresh meat?
<speaker>Young Zuko</speaker>	<sd>[Zuko is shown standing up.]</sd> You can't sacrifice an entire division like that! Those soldiers love and defend our nation! How can you betray them?
<sd>Camera shows everyone in the war room staring at Zuko, save for Iroh, who is kneeling behind his nephew. The scene changes back to the present time.</sd>
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	Zuko was right, you see, <sd>[Massages his beard again.]</sd> but it was not his place to speak out. And there were dire consequences. <sd>[Slightly bows his head.]</sd></scene>

<scene><sd>The flashback ends, and the scene changes to on Zuko's ship. A flashback appears of the fire in front of the Fire Lord's throne rising.</sd>
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	After Zuko's outburst in the meeting, the Fire Lord became very angry with him. <sd>[Flashback quickly ends.]</sd> He said the challenge against the general was an act of complete disrespect! And there was only one way to resolve this.
<speaker>Jee</speaker>	Agni Kai. A fire duel.
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	That's right. Zuko looked upon the old general he had insulted and declared that he was not afraid. But Zuko misunderstood. <sd>[Flashback shows an overview of the chamber; the camera cuts to show Zuko preparing for the Agni Kai.]</sd> When he turned to face his opponent, he was surprised to see it was not the general. <sd>[Flashback shows the tippet that was on Zuko's shoulders fall down to the ground.]</sd> Zuko had spoken out against the general's plan, but by doing so in the Fire Lord's war room, it was the Fire Lord whom he had disrespected. <sd>[Frontal shot of a surprised Zuko; as the camera zooms in on him, his expression changes to one of fear.]</sd> Zuko would have to duel his own father.
<sd>Cut to a wall of the cave. </sd></scene>

<scene><sd>Scene changes back to Zuko's ship.</sd>
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	When Prince Zuko saw that it was his father who had come to duel him, he begged for mercy.
<sd>Flashback shows a side overview of the Agni Kai chamber where Ozai is advancing on Zuko.</sd>
<speaker>Young Zuko</speaker>	<sd>[Cut to a side-view of Zuko.]</sd> Please, Father. I only had the Fire Nation's best interest at heart. I'm sorry I spoke out of turn! <sd>[Slightly lowers his head.]</sd>
<sd>Cut to a frontal shot from a worm's eye perspective of Ozai's silhouette walking up to Zuko.</sd>
<speaker>Ozai</speaker>	You will fight for your honor.
<speaker>Young Zuko</speaker>	<sd>[Frontal shot; kneels on his knees and forearms, while looking at the floor.]</sd> I meant you no disrespect. <sd>[Gazes up at his father, tears shimmering in his eyes as his voice starts to waver.]</sd> I am your loyal son.
<speaker>Ozai</speaker>	<sd>[Far off frontal shot of Zuko as Ozai's shadow and eventually his head come into view.]</sd> Rise and fight, Prince Zuko!
<sd>Cut to a side-view from behind some of the spectators as Ozai reaches Zuko, who lowers his head to the floor again.</sd>
<speaker>Young Zuko</speaker>	I won't fight you.
<speaker>Ozai</speaker>	You will learn respect, <sd>[Zuko pushes himself up on his knees and hands. Cut to a frontal shot of Zuko as he starts to shake.]</sd> and suffering will be your <sd>[Zuko looks up at Ozai, tears streaming down his face.]</sd> teacher.
<sd>Cut to a frontal view of Zhao, Iroh, and Azula in the crowd. While Iroh clenches his teeth and looks fearful and worried on Zuko's behalf, Zhao looks on with a smirk on his face, while Azula smiles and raises her left fist in front of her chest in anticipation.</sd>
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	<sd>[Voice-over; Iroh closes his eyes and averts his head to the left.]</sd> I looked away.
<sd>As the sound of a fire blast is heard, Zuko is screaming "no", which echoes. While the faces of the spectators are brightened by the flames, the camera slowly zooms in on Iroh's averted face. The scene switches from the past to the present, where Iroh is sitting in the same manner.</sd>
<speaker>Jee</speaker>	I always thought that Prince Zuko was in a training accident.
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	It was no accident. After the duel, the Fire Lord said that by refusing to fight, Zuko had shown shameful weakness. As punishment, he was banished and sent to capture the Avatar. Only then could he return with his honor.
<speaker>Jee</speaker>	So that's why he's so obsessed. Capturing the Avatar is the only chance he has of things returning to normal.
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	Things will never return to normal. But the important thing is the Avatar gives Zuko hope.
<sd>Scene changes to show Zuko meditating, while having flashbacks of his younger life. He is stopped by a hit on the ship.</sd></scene>

<scene><sd>Scene changes to Zuko's ship, with Zuko on the deck.</sd>
<speaker>Zuko</speaker>	Where were we hit?
<speaker>Jee</speaker>	I don't know!
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	Look!
<speaker>Zuko</speaker>	The helmsman!
<sd>Zuko and Lieutenant Jee are shown climbing up a ladder to help a man who is about to fall. Lightning goes down to the middle of the ship, where Iroh is. He uses redirection so it does not damage the ship.</sd> 
<sd>Zuko is shown spotting Appa.</sd>
<speaker>Zuko</speaker>	The Avatar!
<speaker>Jee</speaker>	What do you want to do, sir?
<speaker>Zuko</speaker>	Let him go. We need to get this ship to safety.
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	Then we must head directly into the eye of the storm.</scene>

<scene><sd>Scene changes to Zuko and Iroh together.</sd>
<speaker>Zuko</speaker>	Uncle, I'm sorry.
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	Your apology is accepted.</scene>

    </transcript>
</avatarEpisode12>
