<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<avatarEpisode19>
    <transcript>
<scene><sd>Cuts inside a room where Zuko prepares a boat, winding up some rope. Iroh enters.</sd>
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	If you're fishing for an octopus my nephew, you need a tightly woven net, or he will squeeze through the tiniest hole and escape.
<speaker>Zuko</speaker>	I don't need your wisdom right now, Uncle.
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	I'm sorry. I just nag you, because ... well, <sd>[Voice breaking slightly.]</sd> ever since I lost my son ...
<speaker>Zuko</speaker>	Uncle, you don't have to say it.
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	... I think of you as my own.
<speaker>Zuko</speaker>	<sd>[Faces his uncle, a softer expression on his face.]</sd> I know, Uncle. We'll meet again. <sd>[Iroh hugs him.]</sd> After I have the Avatar. <sd>[He turns away and gets on the boat.]</sd>
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	Remember your breath of fire. It could save your life out there.
<speaker>Zuko</speaker>	I will. <sd>[Lowers the boat, suspended by ropes, down the side of the ship into the water.]</sd>
<speaker>Iroh</speaker>	And put your hood up. Keep your ears warm!
<speaker>Zuko</speaker>	I'll be fine!</scene>

<scene><sd>Back to the Spirit Oasis, rays of sunlight beam down on Zuko, who remains imprisoned in the ice, his head bent down. He feels the heat and sharply raises his head. With a determined look on his face, he breathes steam from his nose, melting the ice quickly. He lands on the ground and fires a blast at Katara, who had her back turned to him at that moment. She turns around swiftly and attempts to deflect the blast by conjuring a water shield; however, she creates the shield too late. The blast sends her slamming into the gate to the Spirit World, knocking her out. Smoke from the impact fills the screen. Cuts to shot of Zuko standing over her, holding Aang by the collar.</sd>
<speaker>Zuko</speaker>	You rise with the moon ... I rise with the sun.
<sd>The scene changes to where Fire Navy ships break through the city wall, their bows crumbling the wall, allowing soldiers armed with spears to rush in.</sd>
<speaker>Zhao</speaker>	The Water Tribe can try to resist the inevitable, but their city will fall today.
<sd>Cuts back to the oasis. Camera focuses on a close-up of Katara, whose eyes suddenly snap open as she regains consciousness, only to realize Aang is gone. She crawls around, desperately searching for him.</sd>
<speaker>Katara</speaker>	Aang!
<sd>Sokka and Yue enter on Appa.</sd>
<speaker>Sokka</speaker>	What happened? Where's Zuko?
<speaker>Katara</speaker>	<sd>[Dismayed.]</sd> He took Aang. He took him right out from under me.</scene>
    </transcript>
</avatarEpisode19>