<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<?xml-model href="../avatar_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<atla>
    <transcript>
        <head>
            <episode n="1">The Awakening</episode>
            <book n="3">Fire</book>
            <source link="https://avatar.fandom.com/wiki/The_Awakening"/>
        </head>
        
        <charlist>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Aang">Aang</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Roku">Roku</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Yue">Yue</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Katara">Katara</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Toph">Toph</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Sokka">Sokka</charList>
        </charlist>
        <body>
            <scene n="1">
<sd>Back in the sea, Aang struggles to stay above water or reach his glider. After letting out a scream, a wave overcomes him and he falls into the water. He re-emerges after a brief time.</sd>
<sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr>I'm not gonna make it. I failed. <sd>Within the lightning strikes, the spirit of Roku appears before Aang.</sd> Roku?</sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Roku">Roku</spkr>You haven't failed, Aang.</sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr>But everyone thinks I'm dead again. They think I've abandoned them, and I'm losing this war. I'm letting the whole world down.</sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Roku">Roku</spkr>If anyone is to blame for the state of the world, it is me. I should have seen this war coming and prevented it. You inherited my problems and my mistakes. But I believe you are destined to redeem me and save the world.</sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr>I don't know.</sp>
<sd>Moonlight shines onto Aang as Yue's spirit appears above.</sd>
<sp><spkr ref="Yue">Yue</spkr>You already saved the world. And you'll save the world again, but you can't give up.</sp>
<sd>The storm ends. The spirit of Roku disappears, while Yue's spirit descends toward Aang.</sd>
<sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr><sd>Determined.</sd> You're right. I won't give up.</sp>
<sd>He creates a wave and surfs it with the tree bark. Yue's spirit watches him leave and ascends back to the moon. Aang is washed up at the base of a volcano, on the same crescent island where Roku's temple once was. Later, Momo finds him and licks his face, waking him up. Katara, Sokka, and Toph find him, reaching him via Appa. Katara runs to hug him, her worried look changing to happiness.</sd>
<sp><spkr ref="Katara">Katara</spkr>You're okay!</sp>
<sd>They all, including Momo and Appa, come together for a group hug.</sd>
<sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr>I have so much to do.</sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Katara">Katara</spkr>I know, but you'll have our help.</sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Toph">Toph</spkr>You didn't think you could get out of training just by coming to the Fire Nation, did you?</sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr>What about the invasion?</sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Sokka">Sokka</spkr>We'll join up with my dad and the invasion force the day of the eclipse.</sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Toph">Toph</spkr><sd>Notices Aang's damaged staff has washed ashore.</sd> Hey! What's ... oh, it's your glider.</sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr>It's okay. If someone saw it, it would give away my identity. It's better for now that no one knows I'm alive.</sp>
            </scene>
        </body>
    </transcript>
</atla>