<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../XSLT/Avatar_CSS_7.css"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../XSLT/Avatar_XSLT_07.xsl"?>

<?xml-model href="../avatar_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<atla>
    <transcript>
        <head>
            <episode n="11">The Desert</episode>
            <book n="2">Earth</book>
            <source link="https://avatar.fandom.com/wiki/The_Desert"/>
        </head>
        <charlist>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Sha-Mo">Sha-Mo</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Katara">Katara</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Ghashiun">Ghashiun</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Aang">Aang</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Toph">Toph</charList>
        </charlist>
        <body>
            <scene n="1">
                <sp><spkr ref="Sha-Mo">Sha-Mo</spkr>What are you doing in our land with a sandbender sailer? ‌ From the looks of it, you stole it from the Hami tribe.</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Katara">Katara</spkr>We found the sailer abandoned in the desert. We're traveling with the Avatar. <sd>She gestures at Aang. The leader's eyes widen a bit at this information.</sd> Our bison was stolen and we have to get to Ba Sing Se.</sp>
                <sd>A young man to the right of the leader takes a step forward and aggressively addresses Katara.</sd>
                <sp><spkr ref="Ghashiun">Ghashiun</spkr>You dare accuse our people of theft while you ride in on a stolen sand sailer‌?!</sp>
                <sd>Close-up of Toph's misty, green eye, narrowing as she hears the young man's voice.</sd>
                <sp><spkr ref="Sha-Mo">Sha-Mo</spkr>Quiet, Ghashiun. No one accused our people of anything. If what they say is true, we must give them hospitality.</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Ghashiun">Ghashiun</spkr>Sorry, father.</sp>
                <sd>Toph's eye widens.</sd>
                <sp><spkr ref="Toph">Toph</spkr>I recognize the son's voice. He's the one that stole Appa.</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Katara">Katara</spkr>Are you sure?‌</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Toph">Toph</spkr>I never forget a voice.</sp>
                <sd>Aang's tunic flutters around him as he charges forward, threateningly brandishing his staff toward Ghashiun.</sd>
                <sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr><sd>Angry.</sd> You stole Appa! Where is he? ‌What did you do to him?</sp>
                <sd>Ghashiun cowers back.</sd>
                <sp><spkr ref="Ghashiun">Ghashiun</spkr>They're lying! They're the thieves!</sp>
                <sd>With an angry frown and a growl of frustration, Aang smacks his staff on the ground, obliterating one of the sandbender's sailers with a powerful blade of air.</sd>
                <sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr><sd>Enraged.</sd> Where is my bison‌?</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr>You tell me where he is now!</sp>
                <sd>To emphasize his order, Aang sends a strong blast of air toward another sailer. The sandbenders watch in shock as it blows up.</sd>
                <sp><spkr ref="Sha-Mo:">Sha-Mo:</spkr><sd>To Ghashiun.</sd> What did you do‌?</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Ghashiun">Ghashiun</spkr>I-It wasn't me!</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Toph">Toph</spkr>You said to put a muzzle on him!</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr><sd>Enraged.</sd> You muzzled Appa‌?</sp>
                <sd>Aang's eyes and tattoos start to glow as he enters the Avatar State. With a swing of his staff, he destroys the last of the sandbender's sailers.</sd>
                <sp><spkr ref="Ghashiun">Ghashiun</spkr>I'm sorry! I didn't know that it belonged to the Avatar!</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr><sd>With the voices of all the Avatars.</sd> Tell me where Appa is!</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Ghashiun">Ghashiun</spkr><sd>Frightened.</sd> I traded him! To some merchants! He's probably in Ba Sing Se by now! They were going to sell him there! <sd>The sandbenders raise their hands as if to ward off the Avatar's bright, angry glare.</sd> Please! We'll escort you out of the desert! We'll help however we can!</sp>
                <sd>The wind around Avatar Aang starts the swirl, as his anger is reaching its peak. Sokka pull Toph along with him as he starts to make a break for it, running away from his enraged friend.</sd>
                <sp><spkr ref="Sokka">Sokka</spkr>Just get out of here! Run!</sp>
                <sd>Aang drops his staff. The wind around him forms a fast moving sphere, knocking up sand high into the sky. As everyone runs away, Katara stays put, staring sadly at the ground. The sandstorm engulfs her and Aang completely, obscuring them from the sight of the others. They brace themselves as the whirlwind swoops over them.</sd>
                <sd>Aang's air sphere slowly lifts him up in the air, his teeth clenched and his hands cramped with rage. Katara grabs his right arm, preventing him from rising any further. The terrible face of an outraged Avatar looks down upon her, only to be met by Katara's sincere, sad expression. She pulls him back to the ground and presses him close against her chest. Sokka and Toph lower their arms as the wind becomes less violent. Tears are streaming down the Avatar's glowing eyes. Katara tries her best to hold on as her own tears well up. The air sphere slowly dissolves away as Aang leaves the Avatar state. His rage subsides to make room for pure, heartbreaking sadness.</sd>
                <sd>Fade to credits.</sd>
            </scene>
        </body>
    </transcript>
</atla>
