<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../XSLT/Avatar_CSS_7.css"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../XSLT/Avatar_XSLT_07.xsl"?>

<?xml-model href="../../avatar_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<atla>
    <transcript>
        <head>
            <episode n="12">The Storm</episode>
            <book n="1">Water</book>
            <source link="https://avatar.fandom.com/wiki/The_Storm"/>
        </head>
        <charlist>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Aang">Aang</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Gyatso">Gyatso</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Tashi">Tashi</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Pasang">Pasang</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Katara">Katara</charList>
        </charlist>
        <body>
            <scene n="1">
                <sd>Cut to a wall of the cave. The shot pans down to show Katara and a sad-looking
                    Aang around their campfire. While Momo is asleep in his lap, Aang stares off
                    into the fire with unseeing eyes as he continues his story.</sd>
                <sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr>Then, just when I was feeling better, something
                    worse happened.</sp>
                <sd>Scene changes to flashback of Monk Tashi and Monk Gyatso speaking to Monk
                    Pasang.</sd>
                <sp><spkr ref="Gyatso">Gyatso</spkr>Aang needs to have freedom and fun. He needs to
                    grow up as a normal boy.</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Tashi">Tashi</spkr>You cannot keep protecting him from his
                    destiny.</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Pasang">Pasang</spkr>Gyatso, I know you mean well, but you are
                    letting your affection for the boy cloud your judgment.</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Gyatso">Gyatso</spkr>All I want is what is best for him.</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Pasang">Pasang</spkr>But what we need is what's best for the world.
                    You and Aang must be separated! The Avatar will be sent away to the Eastern Air
                    Temple to complete his training.</sp>
                <sd>Aang is shown looking through a hole in the ceiling, shocked at the news that he
                    just heard.</sd>
                <sp><spkr ref="Katara">Katara</spkr>That's awful, Aang. I don't know what to
                    say.</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr><sd>Stands up.</sd> How could they do that to me?
                    They wanted to take away everything I knew and everyone I loved! <sd>He
                        activates the Avatar State.</sd></sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Katara">Katara</spkr>Whoa! Hot cinders!</sp>
                <sd>Aang comes out of the Avatar State, walks to the fire, and sits down again.</sd>
                <sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr>I'm sorry I got so mad.</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Katara">Katara</spkr>You have the right to be angry after the monks
                    sent you away like that.</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr>Well, that's not exactly what happened.
                        <sd>Flashback starts again, showing Aang looking out the window of his
                        bedroom.</sd> I was afraid and confused. I didn't know what to do.</sp>
                <sd>Flashback shows Aang lying on his bed before changing to Gyatso walking to
                    Aang's room.</sd>
                <sp><spkr ref="Gyatso">Gyatso</spkr>Aang, I'm not going to let them take you away
                    from me. Aang? <sd>Gyatso is shown opening the door more, spotting the scroll,
                        and opening it up. He gasps, and sees a storm coming outside the
                        window.</sd></sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr><sd>Still in present, but flashback playing
                        still.</sd> I never saw Gyatso again. <sd>Flashback shows Aang and Appa
                        through the storm, and how Aang got into the iceberg.</sd> Next thing I
                    knew, I was waking up in your arms after you found me in the iceberg.</sp>
                <sd>Flashback shows Katara's face that was seen in "The Boy in the Iceberg". The
                    flashback ends.</sd>
                <sp><spkr ref="Katara">Katara</spkr>You ran away.</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr>And then the Fire Nation attacked our temple. My
                    people needed me and I wasn't there to help.</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Katara">Katara</spkr>You don't know what would have-.</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr>The world needed me and I wasn't there to help.</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Katara">Katara</spkr>Aang ...</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr>The fisherman was right! I did turn my back on the
                    world!</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Katara">Katara</spkr>You're being too hard on yourself, even if you
                    did run away. I think it was meant to be. If you had stayed, you would have been
                    killed along with all the other airbenders.</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr>You don't know that.</sp>
                <sp><spkr ref="Katara">Katara</spkr>I know it was meant to be this way. The world
                    needs you now. You give people hope.</sp>
            </scene>
        </body>
    </transcript>
</atla>
