<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../XSLT/Avatar_CSS_7.css"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../XSLT/Avatar_XSLT_07.xsl"?>

<?xml-model href="../avatar_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<atla>
    <transcript>
            <head>
                <episode n="3">The Southern Air Temple</episode>
                <book n="1">Water</book>
                <source link="https://avatar.fandom.com/wiki/The_Southern_Air_Temple"/>
            </head>
        <charlist>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Sokka">Sokka</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Aang">Aang</charList>
        </charlist>
        <body>
            <scene n="1">
<sd>Aang enters the room and looks around with a sad expression on his face. The scene switches to a closer shot of the skeleton in the snow and slowly zooms in on it. The skeleton is adorned with a round necklace that supports the symbol of airbending. Close-up of Aang, as he stares at the skeletons. Cut back to a close-up of the skeleton dressed in yellow monk robes. The camera focuses on the round, wooden necklace. Cut back to Aang, whose eyes are trembling with sadness and hold back tears.</sd>
<sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr><sd>Devastated.</sd> Gyatso.</sp>
<sd>The view changes to one from beside the skeleton; its fingers are clearly visible in the front as Aang drops to his knees in the background and lets out a mournful sigh. Cut to Sokka, who pulls the drapes aside and looks around.</sd>
<sp><spkr ref="Sokka">Sokka</spkr><sd>Happily.</sd> Hey, Aang! You find my dinner yet? <sd>Cut to a side-view of Aang sitting on his knees, his head cupped in his hands. Sokka walks toward him. Reassuring.</sd> Aang, I wasn't really going to eat the lemur, okay? <sd>He approaches Aang with a smile on his face, but shakes his head and does a double take.</sd> Oh, man. <sd>Switch to a shot of the skeleton of the monk, which slowly moves back to reveal that Sokka places a hand on Aang's shoulder.</sd> Come on, Aang. Everything will be all right. Let's get out of here.</sp>
<sd>Suddenly, Aang's arrow tattoos begin to glow a bluish white. Cut to a frontal view of Aang, as he lifts his head, his eyes glowing in the same color. The camera pans up; Sokka retracts his hands and gasps for air in fright. Switch to an overview shot of inside the sanctuary where Katara is walking down the circular pattern of statues. She stops before and looks at the statue of Avatar Roku. Cut to a close-up of the statue's face. The camera's point of view switches to behind Roku's shoulder. Katara suddenly looks surprised as a bluish, white light illuminates her face; it seems to come from the statue. Cut back to a close-up of the statue. Its eyes are gleaming bright. The bright light spreads to the other statues and one by one, their eyes start to gleam. The camera pans up to reveal how the light travels from statue to statue and makes its way up to the top of the sanctuary. The camera's point of view switches again to behind Roku's shoulder to show Katara, who is still staring at Roku in shock.</sd>
</scene>
        </body>
    </transcript>
</atla>