<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<?xml-model href="../avatar_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<atla>
    <transcript>
        <head>
            <episode n="6">The Avatar and the Firelord</episode>
            <book n="3">Fire</book>
            <source link="https://avatar.fandom.com/wiki/The_Avatar_and_the_Fire_Lord"/>
        </head>
        
        <charlist>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Aang">Aang</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Sozin">Sozin</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Roku">Roku</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Iroh">Irooh</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Zuko">Zuko</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Katara">Katara</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Sokka">Sokka</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Toph">Toph</charList>
        </charlist>
        <body>
            <scene n="1">
<sp><spkr ref="Sozin">Sozin</spkr>Without you, all my plans are suddenly possible. <sd>Cut to Roku.</sd> I have a vision for the future, Roku.</sp>
<sd>Sozin's dragon appears. As Roku kneels, Sozin mounts the dragon and flies away. Cut to Roku, on the side of the volcano. He is surrounded by toxic gas, and behind him a surge of rock and ash flows swiftly toward him. Cut to a shot of the black clouds billowing from the island, as Sozin's dragon emerges from the plumes. The camera zooms to an extreme close-up of Sozin's eye. Shot cuts to Roku, from the back, still on his knees. He is coughing, and is unable to get to his feet. Fang appears from the right, and flies above him. Cut to a close-up of Roku from the side, as he looks up toward his dragon. Cut to an aerial view of the debris, rapidly approaching Avatar Roku. With the rock avalanche just moments away from swallowing Roku, Fang flies down, and wraps himself around Roku. The wave of ash and rubble cover the two completely, killing both of them. Fade to a bright light, as the camera pans to show an arched window frame. A baby's cries can be heard. The camera pans down to show a smiling born infant.</sd>
<sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr>Who's ... wait, that's me, isn't it? <sd>Cut to a long shot of three Air Nomads. A nun holds up the baby to the light while two people, presumably the infant's parents, stand in the shadows.</sd></sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Roku">Roku</spkr>Make sense of our past, Aang. <sd>Cut to Roku and Aang.</sd> And you will bring peace, and restore balance in the world. <sd>He slowly disappears.</sd></sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr>Roku? Roku!</sp>
<sd>Aang walks out of the flashback into whiteness as the scene changes to Zuko reading in the Dragonbone Catacombs.</sd>
<sp><spkr ref="Sozin">Sozin</spkr>With Roku gone, and the great comet returning, the timing was perfect to change the world. <sd>Cut to Sozin, standing on a balcony, from the behind, looking at his soldiers and the Fire Navy ships.</sd> I knew the next Avatar would be born an Air Nomad. So I wiped out the Air Temples. <sd>Scene changes to a burning temple. The camera slowly fades into an extreme close-up of Sozin's face.</sd> But somehow, the new Avatar eluded me. <sd>Scene changes to Fire Navy ships searching in the polar regions.</sd> I wasted the remainder of my life searching in vain. <sd>Cut to underside of the ship.</sd> I know he's hiding out there somewhere. <sd>Camera pans below to show the iceberg Aang was trapped in.</sd> The Fire Nation's greatest threat ... the last airbender.</sp>
<sd>Fade to a close-up of the scroll Zuko is reading.</sd>
<sp><spkr ref="Zuko">Zuko</spkr>That can't be it! Where's the rest of it? <sd>He searches the scroll to find more information.</sd></sp>
<sd>Zuko puts the scroll down and stands up, as the camera pans out. Scene changes to the Fire Nation prison, where Iroh is imprisoned. Cut to Zuko from the behind, slamming the door to the cell behind him as he enters. Cut to Iroh sitting with his head down.</sd>
<sp><spkr ref="Zuko">Zuko</spkr><sd>Angrily.</sd> You sent this, didn't you? I found the secret history, which by the way should be renamed history most people already know! The note said that I needed to know about my great-grandfather's death, but he was still alive in the end.</sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Iroh">Iroh</spkr><sd>Looking up at Zuko.</sd> No. He wasn't.</sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Zuko">Zuko</spkr><sd>Confused.</sd> What are you talking about?</sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Iroh">Iroh</spkr>You have more than one great-grandfather, Prince Zuko. Sozin was your father's grandfather. <sd>Cut to a bewildered Zuko.</sd> Your mother's grandfather was Avatar Roku.</sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Zuko">Zuko</spkr><sd>Shocked.</sd> Why are you telling me this?</sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Iroh">Iroh</spkr>Because understanding the struggle between your two great-grandfathers can help you better understand the battle within yourself. <sd>Zuko sits down, with his head facing down.</sd> Evil and good are always at war inside you, Zuko. It is your nature, your legacy. But, there is a bright side. <sd>Zuko looks up.</sd> What happened generations ago can be resolved now, by you. Because of your legacy, you alone can cleanse the sins of our family and the Fire Nation. Born in you, along with all the strife, is the power to restore balance to the world.</sp>
<sd>Cut to a bundle inside of a brick wall. Iroh removes a brick and reaches for the bundle. Cut to Iroh slowly unwrapping the bundle, revealing the once-lost headdress, while he walks toward Zuko.</sd>
<sp><spkr ref="Iroh">Iroh</spkr>This is a royal artifact. It's supposed to be worn <sd>Zuko stands.</sd> by the Crown Prince.</sp>
<sd>Zuko takes the headdress from Iroh's hand, and holds the artifact, as the shot cuts to Zuko from the behind, standing outside of Iroh's cell. Iroh stands quietly, looking at his nephew. Cut to a shot of the hardened lava wave the gang had been sitting on. Cut to a shot of Sokka, Katara, and Toph all facing Aang as the camera pans down.</sd>
<sp><spkr ref="Katara">Katara</spkr>You mean, after all Roku and Sozin went through together, even after Roku showed him mercy, Sozin betrayed him like that‌?</sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Toph">Toph</spkr><sd>Cut to Toph.</sd> It's like these people are born bad.</sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr><sd>Cut to Aang from the side, with Sokka standing near him.</sd> No, that's wrong. I don't think that was the point of what Roku showed me at all.</sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Sokka">Sokka</spkr><sd>Shrugging.</sd> Then what was the point?</sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr><sd>Cut to Katara, Toph and Sokka from the behind, as Aang speaks.</sd> Roku was just as much Fire Nation as Sozin was, right? If anything, their story proves anyone's capable of great good and great evil. <sd>Cut to an aerial shot of the hardened lava wave.</sd> Everyone, even the Fire Lord and the Fire Nation have to be treated like they're worth giving a chance. <sd>Shot cuts to a close-up of Aang's face.</sd> And I also think it was about friendships.</sp>
            </scene>
        </body>
    </transcript>
</atla>