<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<?xml-model href="../avatar_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<atla>
    <transcript>
        <head>
            <episode n="21">Sozin's Comet Part 4: Avatar Aang</episode>
            <book n="3">Fire</book>
            <source link="https://avatar.fandom.com/wiki/Sozin%27s_Comet,_Part_4:_Avatar_Aang"/>
        </head>
        
        <charlist>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Aang">Aang</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Lion_turtle">Lion turtle</charList>
            <charList type="recurring" id="Ozai">Ozai</charList>
        </charlist>
        <body>
            <scene n="1">
<sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr><sd>With the voices of all previous Avatars.</sd> Fire Lord Ozai, you and your forefathers have devastated the balance of this world, and now you shall pay the ultimate price! <sd>Aang, under control of his past lives, combines all four elements together for his final attack. At the last second, however, he manages to regain control; he comes out of the Avatar State, lets his attack die out, and floats to the ground, freeing Ozai in the process. He now speaks in his normal voice.</sd> No, I'm not gonna end it like this.</sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Ozai">Ozai</spkr>Even with all the power in the world, you are still weak!</sp>
<sd>Ozai moves to attack Aang who senses it with the seismic sense he learned from Toph. He stamps down and lifts a foot up, dragging a pillar of earth along with him, deflecting Ozai's attack and binding him inside the rock. He circles Ozai and proceeds to bind his other hand as Ozai attempts to attack again. He pulls the rocks down into the earth slightly, causing Ozai to kneel. Ozai attempts one final fire breath attack, but Aang uses airbending to stop and approach him and puts one hand on Ozai's forehead, and one on his chest, while he watches in horror.</sd>
<sd>Aang closes his eyes and it flashes back to Aang's meeting with the lion turtle.</sd>
<sp><spkr ref="Lion_turtle">Lion turtle</spkr>In the era before the Avatar, we bent not the elements but the energy within ourselves.</sp>
<sd>The lion turtle places his paw in a similar position to Aang's hands on Ozai using its claws. The claws begin to glow green light as the camera cuts to a close-up of the lion turtle's eye before fading to Aang. Aang's head arches back and blue energy shines out of his eyes and mouth into the sky. Cut to a side-view of the event before cutting to a close-up of Ozai's terrified face as his eyes and mouth begin to shine out red energy. Aang's, followed by Ozai's, bodies become consumed by the blue and red energies. Cut to a wide-view of the area showing half blue and half red energy in the sky.</sd>
<sp><spkr ref="Lion_turtle">Lion turtle</spkr><sd>Aang remembering.</sd> To bend another's energy, your own spirit must be unbendable or you will be corrupted and destroyed.</sp>
<sd>As he speaks, Ozai's energy begins to make its way to Aang's body, consuming the blue and replacing it with red energy. Cut to a view above Aang looking down at his face as the energy reaches his face and continues to cover the beams shining out his mouth and eyes. Cut to a side-view as the red light begins to take control and the blue light diminishes. Cut to close-up of Aang as the red energy has taken over almost completely with just one eye left. The blue energy begins to disappear, but at the last second it blasts out of Aang's eyes, overwhelming the red energy in the process and proceeding to take over Ozai's own body. Cut to a wide shot of the area as Aang completely takes over Ozai's energy and an intense beam of blue energy erupts into the sky. The beam disappears and Ozai falls to the ground as Aang releases him. Ozai attempts to rise and attack, but falls back exhausted and unable to bend.</sd>
<sp><spkr ref="Ozai">Ozai</spkr><sd>Out of breath.</sd> What? What did you do to me?</sp>
<sp><spkr ref="Aang">Aang</spkr>I took away your firebending. You can't use it to hurt or threaten anyone else ever again.</sp>
<sd>Aang steps forward and looks toward the sea as fire spreads on the land below. Aang breathes deeply and enters the Avatar State briefly, showing his control of the ability. Aang begins to bend the water from the ocean below to extinguish the fires. Cut to many shots of the water rising to extinguish the fires. Cut back to Aang as he lowers the water back to its normal level. Cut to a side-view of Aang as the camera zooms out as Momo returns to Aang's shoulder. Cut to the comet flying away as Sokka, Toph, and Suki are seen leaving the airship they were on. Sokka is being carried by the other two due to his broken leg.</sd>
            </scene>
        </body>
    </transcript>
</atla>